Shreyas Vedpathak

04 Jan 2001 | shreyasvedpathak@gmail.com | 9881898291 | Pune, India | LinkedIn ID: shreyasvedpathak Github ID: shreyasvedpathak | Website: shreyasvedpathak.github.io | Stackoverflow: shreyasvedpathak

PROFILE

1+ years of expertise building and implementing deep learning algorithms using TensorFlow and PyTorch. Excited about increasing studies into artificial intelligence. I have solid technical expertise as well as an academic background in Engineering, Statistics, and Machine Learning.

EDUCATION

2018 – present Pune, India	MIT World Peace University, Bachelor of Technology Branch: Computer Science and Technology Current CGPA: 9.47
2016 – 2018	Sir Parashurambhau College, <i>HSC</i>
Pune, India	Percentage: 81%
2005 – 2016	Shivaji English Medium School, SSC
Saswad, India	Percentage: 90%

SKILLS

C++ • Python • Tensorflow • PyTorch • Scikit Learn • MySQL • MongoDB • Flask • Docker • OpenCV

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Nov 2021 – present Ahmedabad, India	 Computer Vision Intern, Upjao Agrotech ☑ Worked on novel problems related to the Agro-industry with Deep Learning as well as traditional computer vision methods with OpenCV. Assisted and worked with: Research and Patent team in ongoing research. Backend team with the development of API and assure that API generates accurate results. Hiring team with the initial screening of the candidates for intern roles.
Aug 2021 – present	Mentor, DeepLearning.AI

California, USA

Helped candidates enrolled in specific Coursera courses by solving their doubts, sharing learning material, and career advices.

Mar 2021 – Jun 2021 Pune, India **Data Analyst Intern,** *Analytics Domain* ☑

Created a web application-based analysis tool that would leverage data from public APIs. Curated course content for Machine Learning and Deep Learning topics at the beginner and intermediate levels. With the produced courses and a variety of user-side features, developed a Learning Management System.

PUBLICATIONS

Jun 2021 Genomics, High Performance Computing and Machine Learning,

UIJRT (United International Journal for Research & Technology) ☑

This paper aims to explore in a very uncomplicated manner, what exactly is genomics, where does high performance computing and machine learning come into picture, current applications and discuss potential future scope.

Nov 2020

PCOcare PCOS Detection and Prediction using Machine Learning Algorithms,

Bioscience Biotechnology Research Communications ☑

Using 5 Machine Learning Algorithms, this research attempts to provide a system that can aid in the early diagnosis and prediction of PCOS therapy based on an optimal and minimal set of parameters.

PATENTS

2022
Ahmedabad, India

A method and system for Encoding and Decoding data on objects by using geometrical shaped markers.

A strong alternative to QR codes, barcodes, and RFIDs for simultaneously tagging, tracking, and recognizing multiple objects using computer vision techniques.

AWARDS

Nov 2020

Best Paper Award,

International Conference on Intelligent Systems, Data Science and Computing □ Best Research Paper Award in Machine Learning Track.

PROJECTS

Nov 2021 – present

AutiScan, Final Year Project 🛮

To collect data on autism-affected Indian children and determine whether or not they have ASD. The candidate's reaction to a reference video is recorded, and their facial landmarks are utilized to classify them using a CNN + RNN deep learning model.

May 2021 – present

Segmentation of Fire and Smoke in Nano-Satellite Imagery using Mask R-CNN

and Res-UNet, Research Project

Image Segmentation Algorithms like Mask R-CNN, UNet, and Deep Residual U-NET were successfully applied and separated natural objects such as clouds, snow, and rivers against smoke caused by a forest fire.

Jul 2021 - Jul 2021

Hardhat Detection: Dynamically Colored Bounding Boxes, Private Project

Detecting hardhats in an image/video/live stream and offering security approval based

on the color of the hardhat.

Jun 2021 – Jul 2021

Loan Management System - Flask API, Private Project

Simple loan management API made with FLASK as the backend and SQLite as the

database. Token-based authentication, with Flask Blueprints for future scaling.

Oct 2020 - Nov 2020

PCOcare: PCOS Detection & Prediction using ML, Research Project ☑

A system that can aid in the early identification and prediction of PCOS treatment is offered. There were several Machine Learning classifiers used. For feature engineering,

the CHI square strategy is employed.

CERTIFICATES

• DeepLearning.AI TensorFlow Developer • TensorFlow: Advanced Techniques ☑

• Generative Adversarial Networks (GANS) ☑

REFERENCES

Dr. Kalpana Thakre, *Professor*, Sinhgad College of Engineering, Pune kalpana sunil@yahoo.com, 9922411355

Shilpa Sonawani, *Associate Professor*, MIT World Peace University, Pune shilpa.sonawani@mitwpu.edu.in, 8698955002